Alex Ortega

contact@alexortega.dev | +56 979961713 | Guadantún 202, Linares, Chile

SKILLS

• HTML	• CSS	JavaScript	React
 Bootstrap 	Node.js	MySQL	MariaDB
MongoDB	Docker	Linux	Github
Photoshop	Agile		

SUMMARY

Web developer with 15 years of self-taught and hands-on experience in designing, developing and managing websites, e-commerce and hosting services. Knowledge in frontend (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React) and backend (Node.js, SQL, Linux, Docker) technologies. Proven skills in agile project management, team leadership and delivering quantifiable results. Currently taking intensive German language courses in Stuttgart, with the goal of joining the German job market.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AT Solutions Remote, Chile

Full Stack Developer

Nov 2023 - May 2024

- Led the successful redesign and migration of the company's web platform.
- Drove a 25% increase in web traffic and a 30% reduction in load times.

Linares, Chile

Full Stack Developer

Jan 2022 - Present

- Designed and implemented custom web and e-commerce solutions for multiple clients.
- Acquired expertise in design tools like Photoshop and cloud technologies like AWS.
- Implemented Docker architectures to improve system scalability and efficiency.
- Led project teams for the successful development and deployment of projects.

Interluz Parral, Chile

Full Stack Developer

Sep 2017 - Jan 2022

- Implemented monitoring systems that reduced service failures by 80%, significantly improving the quality of internet service for clients.
- Redesigned the captive portals for the hotspot network, increasing internet access speeds by 50% and mitigating connection errors.
- Directed teams for the modernization and optimization of the data center.
- Successfully won and executed high-profile government projects for the Ministry of Education, driving substantial company growth.

Tekné Linares, Chile

Full Stack Developer

Dec 2009 - Sep 2017

- Integrated into the local market, supporting multiple companies to establish their web
- presence and significantly expand their sales and services nationwide.

EDUCATION

Saint Thomas Institute. Dec 2007 IT Technician. Talca, Chile **LANGUAGES** English B. Spanish (Native). **CERTIFICATIONS** freeCodeCamp. 2023 JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures. Fundación Telefónica. 2023 Project Management with Agile Methodologies. freeCodeCamp. 2023 Responsive Web Design.

HOBBIES

- Design and construction of drones in my free time, which has allowed me to develop advanced self-taught skills in electronics, programming and 3D design.
- I create 3D figures and objects using 3D printers, and then customize them by hand painting. This self-directed hobby fosters my creativity and artistic skills.